There's magic in believing!
The Last Unicorn is a fantasy, animation, family
film directed by Arthur Rankin, Jr..
A unicorn learns from a riddle-speaking butterfly that she is supposedly the last of her
kind, all the others having been herded away by the monstrous Red Bull.
The unicorn sets out to discover the truth behind the butterfly's words.
She is eventually joined on her quest by Schmendrick, a second-rate magician, and Molly
Grue, a middle-aged woman who dreamed all her life of seeing a unicorn.
Their journey leads them far from home, all the
way to the castle of King Haggard.
Unicorn / Amalthea (voice), played by Mia Farrow.
Schmendrick (voice), played by Alan Arkin.
Molly Grue (voice), played by Tammy Grimes.
Prince Lir (voice), played by Jeff Bridges.
King Haggard (voice), played by Christopher Lee.
Mommy Fortuna (voice), played by Angela Lansbury.
The Last Unicorn is a 1982 animated fantasy film
directed and produced by Arthur Rankin Jr.
and Jules Bass, from a script by Peter S.
Beagle adapted from his 1968 novel of the same title.
The plot concerns a unicorn who, upon learning that she is the last of her species on
Earth, goes on a quest to find out what has happened to others of her kind.
It was produced by Rankin/Bass Productions for ITC
Entertainment and animated by Topcraft.
Voice performers include Alan Arkin, Jeff Bridges, Mia
Farrow, Angela Lansbury, and Christopher Lee.
The soundtrack was composed and arranged by Jimmy Webb, and songs were performed by the group America
and the London Symphony Orchestra, with additional vocals provided by Lucy Mitchell.
Although critical reviews were generally positive, the film was a
commercial failure, grossing $6.5 million in the United States.
It has since maintained a cult following.
In 2003, the Online Film Critics Society ranked the film as
the 96th greatest animated film of all time.
The film explores themes of love of one's life, magic,
magic show, prince, sorcerer's apprentice.